

SOFTWARE + DATA

★ Stockholm, Sweden | ■ igor@fer.st | % igor.fer.st | ♠ igorferst | ★ i

Summary _

I'm an experienced engineer who loves helping data scientists and analysts extract insights from complex, large-scale data. I've spent 13 years supporting technical data needs across a variety of domains (insurance, healthcare, capital markets, and others) as a data engineer, software engineer, and entrepreneur.

I have deep experience across the entire data stack: designing and building pipelines, ETL, data modeling, and executing analytics/data science projects. I focus on aligning technical work with business needs, and enjoy engaging directly with data users around requirement gathering and validation, training and upskilling, etc.

Work Experience _____

Epidemic Sound Stockholm, Sweden

Sr. Analytics Engineer Sept. 2023 - present

Epidemic's analytics engineering team owns our data warehouse and supports Epidemic's analysts and data scientists with tooling, data products, and expertise.

- Implemented new data warehouse deployment process that increased deployment frequency from twice a week to daily.
- Responsible for all data modeling and data integration in support of new CRM tool implementation.
- Technologies include: dbt, Airflow, BigQuery, Looker, Terraform

Bridgestone Mobility Solutions

Stockholm, Sweden

SR. DIRECTOR OF ENGINEERING/DATA ENGINEERING LEAD

Feb. 2021 - Aug. 2023

My startup Mobikit was acquired and its product incorporated into Bridgestone's software portfolio as a data-driven fleet risk management product for insurance carriers. At Bridgestone, I continued to lead data engineering and product development.

- Oversaw the design and implementation of our telematics data pipeline, with a focus on scalability, reliability, and observability.
- Managed globally distributed team of data and product engineers: hiring, onboarding, coaching, optimizing processes.
- Technologies include: Python (Django/DRF/pandas), SQL (PostgreSQL), AWS serverless/RDS/EC2/Kinesis/Glue, Docker

Mobikit Columbus (OH), USA

Co-Founder/CTO Jan. 2019 - Feb. 2021

Technical co-founder of a startup building a data analytics platform for large-scale vehicle telematics data. I oversaw data engineering, product development, and customer implementation.

- Architected and led development of data pipeline to ingest, harmonize, and enrich telematics data from heterogenous sources.
- Defined and validated data model with current and prospective customers.
- Oversaw design and development of platform's analytics features and executed ad-hoc analytics and data science projects.
- Contributed code across the entire stack, from data pipeline to ETL to application backend to UI.
- Grew and managed globally distributed team of developers.
- Raised funding, guided company to product-market fit, and exited successfully.
- Technologies include: Python (Django/DRF/pandas), SQL (PostgreSQL), AWS serverless/RDS/EC2, Docker, Javascript (React)

Root Insurance Columbus (OH), USA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER/DATA ENGINEER

Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Worked at a growth-stage insuretech unicorn on various data-intensive projects.

- Prototyped a machine learning model to enhance insurance rate accuracy.
- Implemented support for new rating methodologies and executed historical backtests for rating changes.
- Python SME for engineering and actuarial teams.
- Technologies include: Ruby (Rails), Python (scikit-learn), Ansible

Enlace Health Columbus (OH), USA

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sept. 2014 - Feb. 2018

Enlace is a healthtech company building large-scale data analytics tools to support innovative models of healthcare delivery. I joined as an early employee working on the analytics platform, and transitioned to leading a cross-functional team building a care management and revenue cycle management product for surgical centers.

JANUARY 29, 2024 IGOR FERST

InSample San Francisco (CA), USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar. 2014 - Sept. 2014

First employee at a healthcare analytics startup building a cloud-based tool for statistical de-biasing of clinical experiments. Together with the CTO, I interviewed prospective customers, and designed and built the product prototype.

Google Mountain View (CA), USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2014

Part of the conversion tracking team building tools that Google's customers use to understand the effectiveness of their ad spend. I implemented a novel conversion tracking visualization for the AdWords suite of analytics tools and developed enhancements to the Google Analytics machine learning algorithm for attribution modeling.

Palantir Technologies

Palo Alto (CA), USA

FORWARD DEPLOYED ENGINEER

Jan. 2011 - Jan. 2013

I worked on Palantir Metropolis, a data integration and quantitative research platform for capital markets. I was a developer and product owner for the platform's visualization and reporting features, and was embedded with the platform's largest customer, a prominent global macro hedge fund.

Skills_

General Data engineering, software engineering, product management, data science, technical leadership

Languages Python (primary), SQL, Javascript, Ruby, Java

Data dbt, BigQuery, PostgreSQL, Looker

Frameworks Django/DRF, Pandas, React, Rails **Infrastructure** AWS, GCP, Docker, Airflow, Terraform

Technical Expertise Statistics, optimization, machine learning, data modeling, graph algorithms

Education

Cornell University

Ithaca (NY), USA

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- PhD candidate in Applied Mathematics supported by a US National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship.
- Published original research in algorithms and optimization: https://tinyurl.com/ycheu4us

University of Waterloo

Waterloo (Ontario), Canada

M.Math. in Combinatorics & Optimization

University of Chicago

Chicago (IL), USA

Columbus (OH), USA

B.S. IN MATHEMATICS WITH HONORS

United Schools Network

Volunteering

Odesa Peace Fund Stockholm, Sweden

• General IT guidance and support for a US-based nonprofit providing humanitarian aid to Ukraine.

Hack OHI/O Columbus (OH), USA

• Twice served as judge and mentor for Ohio State University's student hackathon.

• Designed and taught a three month after-school programming course for middle-school students.

• Developed spreadsheet-based operational tools for school administrators.

Columbus Arts Festival Columbus (OH), USA

• Built mobile-friendly web-based interactive festival map.

JANUARY 29, 2024 IGOR FERST 2